understandingstandards.org.uk 2016-03-05

# SQA - Understanding Standards: Privacy policy

This Privacy Statement sets out the data processing practices of SQA for the purposes of the Data Protection Act 1998 and related legislation, through the use of the internet and the World Wide Web.  SQA has in place a valid notification with the Information Commissioner in terms of the Data Protection Act 1998. This can be viewed at the data protection website, entering our registration number Z5781759.

Data Protection Act (1998) - Request for access to personal data   
SQA collects personal information from visitors to this website through the use of enquiry and order forms, and every time you e-mail us your details. We may monitor and collect the Internet Protocol (IP) addresses of visitors to our site, and this information may be used for analysis and statistical purposes.

We will use the details you provide us for the provision of information about services, and for administration, sales and marketing. We may need to disclose your details to our agents and other service providers for these purposes. We may assess your suitability for certain services we provide and reserve the right to decline your request if this is considered justified.

We will not share your details with third parties other than those agents and service providers used to meet your requirements. By your provision of personal information to us, you consent to our processing sensitive personal data about you where this is necessary, for example health information, and are protected under the laws of the United Kingdom and other countries.

Given that the internet is a global environment, using the internet to collect and process personal data necessarily involves the transmission of data internationally. Therefore, by browsing this website and communicating electronically with us, you acknowledge and agree to our processing of your personal data in this way.

SQA respects your right of privacy. If you tell us that you do not wish to have your personal information used in the ways we have specified, we will respect your wishes. You have a right to apply for a copy of the information about you that we hold (for which we may charge a small fee) and to have any inaccuracies corrected by contacting us on [data.protection@sqa.org.uk](mailto:data.protection@sqa.org.uk).

If you do not wish to be contacted for marketing purposes, please e-mail us on [mycentre@sqa.org.uk](mailto:mycentre@sqa.org.uk), but remember that if you do so we will be unable to provide you with information about latest publications etc.
